<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>New Approach to OVN Datapath Performance</title>
  <guests>Jun Xiao from CloudNetEngine</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Jun Xiao is the founder and CTO of CloudNetEngine, which is focused on
      innovating a next generation ``engine'' for cloud virtual networking.  He
      has over 15 years experience in VMware, Huawei, Lucent, Sun Microsystem,
      and other companies.  His system design experience ranges from low-level
      device drivers and network stacks to middleware and distributed systems.
    </p>

    <p>
      This episode is a talk that Jun gave at OpenStack Boston during the Open
      vSwitch Open Source Day on May 10, with the following abstract:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      Jun presents a new high-performance datapath for OVN.  OVN has many
      advantages than other virtual networking solutions given its great
      architecture thus performant/extensible/scale, and it becomes the best
      virtual networking solution if you want to use OVS with openstack.  In
      this presentation, Jun will show how to deploy openstack/OVN with yet
      another high performance OVS datapath, and deep dive on technical
      solutions addressing OVS datapaths outstanding issues.  Jun will also
      give a live demo for the integration and present some performance
      benchmarks.
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      Slides for this talk are available in <a
      href="http://openvswitch.org/support/boston2017/1530-jun-xiao.ppt">PowerPoint</a>
      and <a
      href="http://openvswitch.org/support/boston2017/1530-jun-xiao.pdf">PDF</a>
      formats.  The PowerPoint version may be preferable because it preserves
      the animations.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 05:26:12 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
