<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>Oko: Extending Open vSwitch with Stateful Filters</title>
  <guests>Paul Chaignon from Orange Labs and Inria Nancy</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Paul Chaignon is a grad student at Orange and Inria.  In this episode,
      Paul talks about <a
      href="https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3185496">Oko: Extending Open
      vSwitch with Stateful Filters</a>, a paper written with co-authors Kahina
      Lazri, Jérôme François, Thibault Delmas, and Olivier Festor.  Paul
      presented this research at <a
      href="https://conferences.sigcomm.org/sosr/2018/">SOSR '18</a> in March
      2018.  The paper has the following abstract:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      <p>
        With the Software-Defined Networking paradigm, software switches
        emerged as the new edge of datacenter networks. The widely adopted Open
        vSwitch implements the OpenFlow forwarding model; its simple
        match-action abstraction eases network management, while providing
        enough flexibility to define complex forwarding pipelines. OpenFlow,
        however, cannot express the many packets processing algorithms required
        for traffic measurement, network security, or congestion diagnosis, as
        it lacks a persistent state and basic arithmetic and logic operations.
      </p>

      <p>
        This paper presents Oko, an extension of Open vSwitch that enables
        runtime integration of stateful filtering and monitoring
        functionalities based on Berkeley Packet Filter (BPF) programs into the
        OpenFlow pipeline. BPF programs attached to OpenFlow rules act as
        intelligent filters over packets, while leaving the packets
        unmodified. This approach enables the transparent extension of Open
        vSwitch's flow caching architecture, retaining its high-performance
        benefits. Furthermore, the use of BPF allows for safe runtime extension
        and prevention of switch failures due to faulty programs.
      </p>

      <p>
        We compare our implementation based on Open vSwitch-DPDK to existing
        approaches with comparable isolation properties and measure a near 2x
        improvement of performance.
      </p>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      You can contact Paul on Twitter as <a
      href="https://twitter.com/pchaigno">@pchaigno</a>.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 18:37:31 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
