<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>Long-Term Network Latency</title>
  <guests>Nick Buraglio from ESnet</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Nick Buraglio works in research and education and service provider
      networking, currently at <a href="https://es.net">ESnet</a>, the US
      Department of Energy's science network, which links <a href="https://es.net/about/">sites in the United States and western
      Europe</a>.  In this podcast, he talks about the role of latency
      monitoring in managing a network.
    </p>

    <p>
      Nick defines the latency that he's talking about:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      &quot;When most people think of latency, they think of a ping round-trip time.
      That's one useful data point, but we're talking about very low tolerance
      and high accuracy latency.  You have to have a cellular or GPS clock and
      a very strong clock source in the system to be able to track it at this
      level.  We use that as a very important part of how we manage our
      network.  That's really what I'm talking about when I talk about
      latency.&quot;
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      Nick discusses the <a href="http://docs.perfsonar.net/">perfSONAR</a>
      software for monitoring latency over time and for investigating problems
      as they occur.
    </p>

    <p>
      Some basic live monitoring charts and graphs for ESnet are online at <a href="https://my.es.net/">MyESnet</a>.
    </p>

    <p>
      You can contact Nick on Twitter as <a href="https://twitter.com/forwardingplane">@forwardingplane</a> or visit
      his blog at <a href="https://www.forwardingplane.net/">forwardingplane.net</a>.
    </p>

    <p>
      Other episodes of OVS Orbit related to monitoring include <a href="#e46">Episode 46: In-band Network Telemetry</a> and <a href="#e6">Episode 6: sFlow</a>.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
