<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>Personalized Pseudonyms for Servers in the Cloud</title>
  <guests>Qiuyu Xiao from UNC-Chapel Hill</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Qiuyu Xiao is a PhD student studying computer science at the University
      of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.  This episode is a talk that Qiuyu gave
      at VMware in May.  It is based on the paper ``Personalized Pseudonyms for
      Servers in the Cloud,'' by Qiuyu Xiao, Michael K. Reiter, and Yinqian
      Zhangyinqian, originally published in 2017 at <cite>Proceedings on
      Privacy Enhancing Technologies</cite>.
    </p>

    <p>
      You may wish to follow along with Qiuyu's <a
      href="episode-63-slides.pdf">slides</a>.
    </p>

    <p>
      The paper's abstract is:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      A considerable and growing fraction of servers, especially of web
      servers, is hosted in compute clouds. In this paper we opportunistically
      leverage this trend to improve privacy of clients from network attackers
      residing between the clients and the cloud: We design a system that can
      be deployed by the cloud operator to prevent a network adversary from
      determining which of the cloud’s tenant servers a client is
      accessing. The core innovation in our design is a PoPSiCl (pronounced
      ``popsicle''), a persistent pseudonym for a tenant server that can be used
      by a single client to access the server, whose real identity is protected
      by the cloud from both passive and active network attackers. When
      instantiated for TLS-based access to web servers, our design works with
      all major browsers and requires no additional client-side software and
      minimal changes to the client user experience. Moreover, changes to
      tenant servers can be hidden in supporting software (operating systems
      and web-programming frameworks) without imposing on web-content
      development. Perhaps most notably, our system boosts privacy with minimal
      impact to web-browsing performance, after some initial setup during a
      user’s first access to each web server.
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      You can reach Qiuyu at <a
      href="mailto:qiuyu@cs.unc.edu">qiuyu@cs.unc.edu</a> or on Twitter as <a
      href="https://twitter.com/QiuyuX">@QiuyuX</a>.
    </p>

    <p>
      Related episodes.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 14:01:03 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
