<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>OpenStack Cyborg</title>
  <guests>Howard (Zhipeng) Huang from Huawei</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Howard is an IT standards engineer at Huawei.  He has been working on
      open source for about 6 years and attended the early Open vSwitch
      conferences, including the earliest one held at Cisco in 2014.  In this
      episode of OVS Orbit, Howard talks about the OpenStack Cyborg project in
      OpenStack, which was formerly called Nomad.  Howard is the ``caretaking''
      PTL for the project.
    </p>

    <p>
      The Cyborg project supports all kinds of hardware acceleration for
      OpenStack.  It spans networking, storage, and other areas, primarily
      because users tend to think of acceleration as a single bucket of
      features.  Acceleration features across these multiple areas do require
      common lifecycle management processes, supplied by Cyborg as as a common
      management framework.
    </p>

    <p>
      Open vSwitch relates to Cyborg on the network acceleration angle.  Howard
      says that OVS can benefit from lifecycle management for hardware
      acceleration, especially when the DPDK datapath is involved.  This could
      allow users to ensure that OVS is always properly configured for the
      local hardware.  Even in the absence of special acceleration hardware,
      DPDK requires NIC- and CPU-specific configuration and tuning that amounts
      to a kind of software acceleration, which Cyborg can help to manage.
    </p>

    <p>
      Howard says that the project is planning an initial release for September
      2017, in time for the OpenStack developer meeting.
    </p>

    <p>
      The <a href="https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Cyborg">Cyborg website</a>
      and <a
      href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1xXjqlMaXjXe7mn-iwoETGcTPnTbqCDfpaT6yqlZ8srE/edit#slide=id.p">master
      slide deck</a> are good basic resources for learning about Cyborg.
    </p>

    <p>
      You can contact or follow Howard on Twitter as <a
      href="https://twitter.com/nopainkiller">@nopainkiller</a>.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 19:07:31 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
