<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>Trumpet: Timely and Precise Triggers in Data Center Networks</title>
  <guests>Minlan Yu from Yale</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      <a href="http://www.cs.yale.edu/homes/yu-minlan/">Minlan Yu</a> is an
      associate professor of computer science at Yale and before that at USC.
      She works in several areas that are relevant to Open vSwitch, including
      network virtualization and software-defined networking, enterprise and
      data center networks, and distributed systems.
    </p>

    <p>
      We begin by talking about <a
      href="http://conferences.sigcomm.org/sigcomm/2017/workshop-hotconnet.html">ACM
      SIGCOMM 2017 1st International Workshop on Hot Topics in Container
      Networking and Networked Systems</a>, which Minlan is co-chairing.
      ``HotConNet'' is a new workshop at SIGCOMM this year focusing on
      networking for containers, which is far from a mature field.  The
      workshop is accepting 6-page papers until March 24.  Workshop papers will
      be presented as part of SIGCOMM 2017 in Los Angeles, August 21 to 23.
    </p>

    <p>
      The main topic of discussion is <a
      href="http://www.cs.yale.edu/homes/yu-minlan/writeup/sigcomm16.pdf">Trumpet:
      Timely and Precise Triggers in Data Centers</a>, published at SIGCOMM in
      August 2016.  The abstract for this paper is:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      As data centers grow larger and strive to provide tight performance and
      availability SLAs, their monitoring infrastructure must move from passive
      systems that provide aggregated inputs to human operators, to active
      systems that enable programmed control. In this paper, we propose
      Trumpet, an event monitoring system that leverages CPU resources and
      end-host programmability, to monitor every packet and report events at
      millisecond timescales. Trumpet users can express many <em>network-wide
      events</em>, and the system efficiently detects these events using
      <em>triggers</em> at end-hosts. Using careful design, Trumpet can
      evaluate triggers by inspecting every packet at full line rate even on
      future generations of NICs, scale to thousands of triggers per end-host
      while bounding packet processing delay to a few microseconds, and report
      events to a controller within 10 milliseconds, even in the presence of
      attacks. We demonstrate these properties using an implementation of
      Trumpet, and also show that it allows operators to describe new network
      events such as detecting correlated bursts and loss, identifying the root
      cause of transient congestion, and detecting short-term anomalies at the
      scale of a data center tenant.
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      Afterward, Minlan provides a sneak peak at a paper to be presented at
      NSDI in March, ``CherryPick: Adaptively Unearthing the Best Cloud
      Configurations.''  This paper will present an efficient way to choose the
      best machine type and parameters in a public from among the hundreds of
      configurations offered by large public clouds.
    </p>

    <p>
      Minlan may be contacted via email: minlan.yu (at) yale (dot) edu.  You
      can also follow her <a href="https://twitter.com/minlanyu">on
      Twitter</a>.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 03:01:04 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
