<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>Software Synthesis for Networks</title>
  <guests>Nate Foster from Cornell</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Nate Foster is an Associate Professor of Computer Science at Cornell
      University and a Visiting Researcher at Barefoot Networks. The goal of
      his research is developing programming languages and tools for building
      reliable systems. He received a PhD in Computer Science from the
      University of Pennsylvania in 2009, an MPhil in History and Philosophy of
      Science from Cambridge University in 2008, and a BA in Computer Science
      from Williams College in 2001. His awards include a Sloan Research
      Fellowship, an NSF CAREER Award, a Most Influential POPL Paper Award, a
      Tien ’72 Teaching Award, a Google Research Award, a Yahoo! Academic
      Career Enhancement Award, and the Morris and Dorothy Rubinoff Award.
    </p>

    <p>
      This is a recording of a talk that Nate gave at the <a
      href="http://netseminar.stanford.edu/">Stanford Networking Seminar</a>,
      organized by <a href="mailto:lavanyaj@cs.stanford.edu">Lavanya Jose</a>
      and <a href="mailto:ecidon@stanford.edu">Eyal Cidon</a>, on December 8,
      2016.  <a
      href="http://netseminar.stanford.edu/seminars/12_08_16.pdf">Slides</a>
      and <a href="https://youtu.be/u4l5FtJI48E">video</a> (recorded by the
      organizers) are also available.
    </p>

    <p>
      Nate describes this talk as:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      <p>
        Software synthesis is a powerful technique that can dramatically
        increase the productivity of programmers by automating the construction
        of complex code. One area where synthesis seems particularly promising
        is in computer networks. Although SDN architectures make it possible to
        build rich applications in software, programmers today are forced to
        deal with numerous low-level details such as encoding high-level
        policies using low-level hardware primitives, processing asynchronous
        events, dealing with unexpected failures, etc.
      </p>

      <p>
        This talk will present highlights from recent work using synthesis to
        generate correct-by-construction network programs. In the first part of
        the talk, I will describe an approach for generating configuration
        updates that are guaranteed to preserve specified invariants. In the
        second part of the talk, I will present an extension that supports
        finer-grained updates triggered by data-plane events.
      </p>

      <p>
        Joint work with Pavol Cerny (University of Colorado at Boulder),
        Jedidiah McClurg (University of Colorado at Boulder), Hossein Hojjat
        (Rochester Institute of Technology), Andrew Noyes (Google), and Todd
        Warszawski (Stanford University).
      </p>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      <a href="http://yuba.stanford.edu/~nickm/">Nick McKeown</a> introduces
      the talk.
    </p>

    <p>
      To get the most from this talk, listen to it along while viewing the <a
      href="http://netseminar.stanford.edu/seminars/12_08_16.pdf">slides</a>.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 18:08:13 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
