<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>OVS in Production</title>
  <guests>Chad Norgan from Rackspace</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Interview with Chad Norgan of Rackspace, about use of Open vSwitch at
      Rackspace over the years.
    </p>

    <p>
      Topics include:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        Chad's role at Rackspace and what he spends his time on.
      </li>

      <li>
        Shifts in where he spends his time as Open vSwitch has matured.
      </li>

      <li>
        Experiments with buying and writing SDN controllers and OpenFlow flows
        at Rackspace, including a Ryu-based chassis controller.
      </li>

      <li>
        SDN in two generations of Rackspace cloud, with NVP in the second
        generation.
      </li>

      <li>
        Tracing datapath flows using tools in Open vSwitch, using
        ``<code>ovs-appctl ofproto/trace</code>'', and the value of tracing for
        debugging a running system.
      </li>

      <li>
        Suggestions for improving ``<code>ovs-appctl ofproto/trace</code>''.
      </li>

      <li>
        Usefulness of Open vSwitch logging.
      </li>

      <li>
        Significant performance improvements since earlier versions, such as
        moving logging out of the main thread, megaflows, and eviction
        handling.
      </li>

      <li>
        Potential appliance use of DPDK, contrasted against downside for
        hypervisors of losing a core.
      </li>

      <li>
        Thoughts about importance of 64-byte packet performance in Rackspace
        environment, and potential of eBPF work going on at Cisco to help with
        that.
      </li>

      <li>
        Performance history of Open vSwitch versions as perceived by Nicira and
        Rackspace, and its evolution over time as Open vSwitch was exposed to
        more and more diverse production use cases.
      </li>

      <li>
        Open vSwitch decision for version 1.11 to completely rewrite everything
        in terms of megaflows, to achieve reasonable performance in important
        minority of cases.
      </li>

      <li>
        Chad's presentation on Open vSwitch performance at the <a
        href="http://openvswitch.org/support/ovscon2014/">Open vSwitch 2014
        Fall Conference</a>.
      </li>

      <li>
        Open vSwitch as the ``incumbent'' virtual switch.
      </li>

      <li>
        Generating good representative traffic for testing.
      </li>

      <li>
        Ixia hardware for predictable traffic generation, removing a variable
        from the testing equation.
      </li>

      <li>
        Desire for a physical hardware switch with the flexibility of Open
        vSwitch, with P4 switches as a possible route there.
      </li>

      <li>
        ``<code>ovsdb-tool -mmm show-log</code>'' as database debugging tool.
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      Chad can be contacted at <a
      href="https://twitter.com/chadnorgan">@chadnorgan</a> on Twitter, as
      BeardyMcBeard on the <a href="http://freenode.net">freenode</a> IRC
      network
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro and bumper music is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/myfreemickey/48180">Electro
      Deluxe</a>, featuring Gurdonack, copyright 2014 by My Free Mickey.  The
      outro music is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/JeffSpeed68/44932">Girls like
      you</a>, featuring Thespinwires, copyright 2014 by Stefan Kartenberg.
      All content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
<pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 21:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
