<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>The Evolution of OpenFlow</title>
  <guests>Jean Tourrilhes from HPE Labs and Justin Pettit from VMware</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Jean Tourrilhes is a networking researcher at HPE Labs who served as the
      chair of the Open Networking Foundation's OpenFlow standardization
      working group (the ``extensibility'' working group) from its inception
      until 2015.  Justin Pettit, who was a founding employee at Nicira and who
      has continued to work at VMware since it acquired Nicira in 2012, was
      co-chair of the working group during the same period.
    </p>

    <p>
      Justin and Jean are two of the authors of ``<a
      href="https://www.opennetworking.org/images/stories/downloads/sdn-resources/IEEE-papers/evolution-of-sdn-and-of.pdf">SDN
      and Standards Evolution: a Standards Perspective</a>,'' a paper published
      in IEEE Computer in Nov. 2014.  This paper gives a lot of the facts
      behind the OpenFlow's evolution, but it doesn't talk at all about what
      worked well and what didn't in the standardization process.  This
      discussion tries to cover that part of the story, with the goal of
      helping listeners to understand how they might better approach any future
      standardization processes in the future.
    </p>

    <p>
      Some of the topics covered include:
    </p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        Tension between advocates for hardware and software switch
        implementations.
      </li>

      <li>
        The debates behind multiple table support.
      </li>

      <li>
        Capabilities aka ``table features'' aka ``table type pattern'' support.
      </li>

      <li>
        Will increasing flexibility in hardware enable better OpenFlow-like
        functionality in the future?  At what cost?
      </li>

      <li>
        Naivete regarding OpenFlow influence over hardware.
      </li>

      <li>
        Secretiveness of hardware vendors and the OpenFlow hardware vendor
        working group.
      </li>

      <li>
        The requirement for prototyping new features added to OpenFlow, along
        with pluses and minuses for the requirement.
      </li>

      <li>
        Different categories of switches, beyond ``hardware'' and ``software''
        classification.
      </li>

      <li>
        Interactions with testing and interoperability working group, and
        difficulties with NDAs on testing results.
      </li>

      <li>
        Lack of OpenFlow reference implementation and Open vSwitch de facto in
        that role.
      </li>

      <li>
        Increased power of the working group chair, compared to the IETF.
      </li>

      <li>
        What is the future of OpenFlow?  Is it dying?  Or just entrenched?
      </li>

      <li>
        What's a likely successor to OpenFlow?  P4?  eBPF?
      </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
      You can contact Jean via email as <a
      href="mailto:jt@labs.hpe.com">jt@labs.hpe.com</a> and Justin either via
      email as <a href="mailto:jpettit@ovn.org">jpettit@ovn.org</a> or on
      Twitter as <a
      href="https://twitter.com/Justin_D_Pettit">@Justin_D_Pettit</a>.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 02:53:05 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
