<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>Routing a Production Enterprise Network with Faucet</title>
  <guests>Brad Cowie from WAND</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      <a href="https://wand.nz/~brad/">Brad Cowie</a> is a member of the <a
      href="https://wand.net.nz/">WAND Network Research Group</a> at the <a
      href="https://www.waikato.ac.nz/">University of Waikato</a>, in Hamilton,
      New Zealand.  He is also a core member of the Faucet project which
      develops an open source OpenFlow controller for enterprise networks,
      which he uses to build production OpenFlow networks.
    </p>

    <p>
      This episode is a recording of a <a
      href="https://www.openstack.org/summit/sydney-2017/summit-schedule/events/20415/providing-routing-on-a-production-enterprise-network-with-faucet-and-openvswitch">talk</a>
      that Brad gave at the <a
      href="https://www.openstack.org/summit/sydney-2017/">OpenStack Summit in
      Sydney</a> on Nov. 6, with the following abstract:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      Within the WAND network research group at the University of Waikato, we
      operate a 100% OpenFlow-controlled network for research/teaching/BYOD
      traffic.  The access/aggregation layer of this network is provided by
      vendor OpenFlow switches (most running embedded OpenvSwitch with ASIC SDK
      drivers to drive merchant silicon).  The core routing for the network is
      provided by a linux server running a high-speed userspace OpenvSwitch
      bridge accelerated by DPDK.  The entire network is controlled by our open
      source OpenFlow v1.3 controller, Faucet.  We also introduce our
      test-driven methodology for implementing network features in Faucet and
      how this can also be applied to operating a network.
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      You may want to view the <a
      href="https://wand.nz/~brad/talks/openstack_summit_sydney2017_faucet.pdf">slides</a>
      that accompany the talk.
    </p>

    <p>
      For more information on Faucet, visit the <a
      href="http://faucet.nz/">Faucet website</a>.  You can reach Brad as
      <code>gizmoguy</code> on IRC or <a
      href="https://twitter.com/nzgizmoguy">@nzgizmoguy</a> on Twitter.
    </p>

    <p>
      OVS Orbit has previously covered Faucet in <a href="#e45">Episode 45:
      Faucet and OpenFlow at Allied Telesis</a>, <a href="#e33">Epsiode 33:
      Lightning Talks</a>, and <a href="#e19">Episode 19: The Faucet SDN
      Controller</a>.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 21:26:10 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
