<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>OVN Support for Multiple Gateways and IPv6</title>
  <guests>Russell Bryant and Numan Siddique from Red Hat</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Russell Bryant is a Senior Principal Software Engineer at Red Hat, Inc.
      He was on the OpenStack Technical Committee from Fall 2012 until Fall
      2016 and was elected to serve on the OpenStack Foundation Board of
      Directors in 2015, 2016, and 2017.  Russell has been contributing to the
      development of OpenStack since the Fall of 2011.  His most significant
      contributions around OpenStack have been to Nova and most recently
      Neutron and OVN.  Russell is also a project committer for Open vSwitch
      (OVS) and OVN.
    </p>

    <p>
      Numan Siddique is a developer at Red Hat, Bangalore.  He has around 12
      years of software development experience.  He has been involved with
      OpenStack since Ice house release.  He works mainly on OVN and
      networking-ovn. Prior to OVN, he was contributing to OpenContrail SDN
      controller.
    </p>

    <p>
      This episode is a talk that Russell and Numan gave at OpenStack Boston
      during the Open vSwitch Open Source Day on May 10, with the following
      abstract:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      <p>
        OVN supports multiple gateways on a network with traffic spread across
        them.  Russell Bryant will cover the different gateway and NAT modes
        supported by OVN and how OpenStack can take advantage of multiple
        gateway support.
      </p>

      <p>
        OVN supports IPv6.   Numan Siddique will cover the details of this
        support, the present status of the IPv6 features supported and a list
        of missing IPv6 features if any and a demo showing the supported IPv6
        features by OVN.
      </p>
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      Slides for this talk are available in <a
      href="http://openvswitch.org/support/boston2017/1150-ovn-gateways-ipv6.pdf">PDF</a>
      format.  Some parts of the talk will be easier to follow while looking at
      the slides.
    </p>

    <p>
      Toward the end of the questions, Russell refers to the talk <a
      href="https://www.openstack.org/videos/boston-2017/openstack-and-ovn-whats-new-with-ovs-2-7">OpenStack
      and OVN: What's New with OVS 2.7</a>, given by Russell Bryant, Ben Pfaff,
      and Justin Pettit at OpenStack Summit Boston.
    </p>

    <p>
      Russell previously appeared in <a href="#e18">episode 18</a>, on the
      launch of OVN, and <a href="#e7">episode 7</a> was based on a talk that
      he co-presented.  Russell also made multiple presentations at <a
      href="http://openvswitch.org/support/ovscon2015/">Open vSwitch 2015 Fall
      Conference</a>.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 18:17:01 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
