<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<item xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <title>Open Compute Project Networking</title>
  <guests>Andrew "Puck" Ruthven from Catalyst IT</guests>
  <description>
    <p>
      Andrew Ruthven, aka ``Puck'', is a Data Centre Manager at <a
      href="https://www.catalyst.net.nz/">Catalyst IT</a>, a New Zealand open
      source specialist IT company whose services include operating an
      OpenStack based public cloud.
    </p>

    <p>
      This episode is based on <a
      href="https://www.openstack.org/summit/sydney-2017/summit-schedule/events/20417/open-compute-project-down-under">``Open
      Compute Project, down under''</a>, a talk that Andrew gave at OpenStack
      Sydney, which had the following abstract:
    </p>

    <blockquote>
      This talk will review the Open Compute Project, where it came from, where
      things are now and where things are headed. We will cover benefits that
      Open Compute Project hardware provide over the typical server hardware
      that we’re used to. We will discuss how it works for the large scale
      operators, and the issues that affect the small scale operators from the
      perspective of a small scale operator.
    </blockquote>

    <p>
      The discussion begins with an introduction to the Open Compute Project
      (OCP) and its history and motivations.  Andrew covers challenges in
      bringing the Open Compute Project to New Zealand, which included setting
      up supply and support chains for the hardware.  More relevant to our
      podcast focus, in addition to servers, OCP includes hardware for ``white
      box'' switches and access points, and Andrew talks about how those work
      and how they fit into a data center infrastructure.  Andrew also talks
      about the future of OCP and SDN at Catalyst and in New Zealand.
    </p>

    <p>
      Toward the end, we digress into a side discussion of how, on the
      commercial side of the industry, hardware is becoming more and more open,
      with OCP as an example, whereas on the consumer side, hardware is
      becoming more and more locked down, and Andrew and Ben offer their
      thoughts on the situation.
    </p>

    <p>
      You can find Andrew on Twitter as <a
      href="https://twitter.com/puck_">@puck_</a>.  To find out more about Open
      Compute Project, visit the <a href="http://www.opencompute.org/">project
      website</a>.
    </p>

    <p class="attribution">
      OVS Orbit is produced by <a href="mailto:blp@ovn.org">Ben Pfaff</a>.  The
      intro music in this episode is <a
      href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/AlexBeroza/43098">Drive</a>,
      featuring cdk and DarrylJ, copyright 2013, 2016 by Alex.  The bumper
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/speck/42100">Yeah Ant</a>
      featuring Wired Ant and Javolenus, copyright 2013 by Speck.  The outro
      music is <a href="http://dig.ccmixter.org/files/Kirkoid/43005">Space
      Bazooka</a> featuring Doxen Zsigmond, copyright 2013 by Kirkoid.  All
      content is licensed under a Creative Commons <a
      href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Attribution 3.0
      Unported (CC BY 3.0)</a> license.
    </p>
  </description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 11:18:17 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
